Stuart Robinson

http://sturob.com

Creative technologist with deep knowledge of web and mobile platforms and possibilities.

A hybrid designer/developer. Strong UX design skills, a decade of coding for the web, with a keen eye for reusable third-party code and how to innovate but still deliver on schedule.

Digital and startup native with big picture awareness. Particularly well equipped to: · design innovative new apps and services · rapidly prototype possible solutions · do what it takes to drive development through to deployment

Especially interested in: · touch interfaces · information visualisation · $cryptography + usability \cdot persuasive design \cdot how generative design can$ revolutionise creative industries

Skills

- HTML 5
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- User Experience
- UX
- LESS
- JSON
- MVP
- Digital Art
- Paper Prototyping
- Perl
- SVG

- User Interface
- CSS
- Mobile Applications
- HTML5
- UI
- Backbone.js
- REST
- Information Visualization Socket.io
- Web Interface Design Mobile Interface Design Service Design
 - Rapid Prototyping
 - Creative Technology
 - Product Management
 - Bitcoin

• Ruby on Rails

jQuery

AJAX

- Git
- unix
- Underscore.js
- API
- Usability
- Generative Design
- Wireframes
- Touch Interfaces
- Front-end

Experience

· freelance ·

01 / 2012 - Present

UI Developer / Product Designer

Helped scope, design and build HTML5-based apps for iOS, mobile and desktop browsers.

Developing a live-coding environment to accelerate creative coding.

OO Javascript, jQuery, backbone.js, underscore.js, HTML5, LESS, CSS, Canvas



lastpixel

12 / 2009 - Present

Founder / Product Lead

Conceived and led creation of Use it or Lose it (http://useitorlose.it). A iPhone app and web site for people to photograph, upload and organize their personal possessions.

Designed and developed an innovative, animated, real-time HTML5 web app and highly optimised HTML5 mobile interface. Integrated both with a Rails-based REST API. Designed the iPhone interface and produced the marketing site.

Wore a lot of hats: marketing, copywriting, app store management, analytics.

HTML5, LESS, CSS, REST, Javascript, jQuery, Sammy.js, Rails

reeplay.it

09 / 2008 - 09 / 2011

Service Designer / Interface Developer

Worked with Rails developers to conceive, design and implement interface improvements and new features for a video saving and sharing site. Including:

 \cdot Maintained interfaces across multiple platforms (web, mobile web, TV wii) \cdot Created touch HTML5 interface for iPad (video browsing and playback) \cdot Created custom visualisations to help understand site usage

jQuery, Javascript, HTML5, LESS, CSS, REST, APIs, Rails

lastpixel

04 / 2008 - 07 / 2008

Owner / Mobile Web Developer

Built a mobile social network around ringtones/wallpapers.

Highly usable on both full desktop browsers and the (complete nightmare at the time) of mobile browsers.

Rails, prototype.js, HTML, AJAX, CSS.

Cominded

04 / 2007 - 02 / 2008

Front-end Developer / Service Designer

Worked with Rails developers to design and implement a clean user interface and create a coherent vision for a Quora style site with Skype integration (yabb.com)

Rails, prototype.js, javascript, CSS, HTML.

Incrediblinc / Reuters

08 / 2006 - 09 / 2006

Contract UI Designer

Redesigned and styled Reuters' internal innovation platform.

Photoshop, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Bandwagon.co.uk

07 / 2005 - 06 / 2006

Technology Lead

Led a team of 5 to architect and successfully deliver a social network and mobile distribution platform for independent musicians.

Responsible for all aspect of the technology required: \cdot scoped site functionality \cdot chose technologies and server architecture \cdot liaised with graphic designers, flash developers, and MMS platform partners \cdot hired developers

Linux, PHP, HTTP, APIs, Javascript, HTML, CSS.

20six weblog services

04 / 2005 - 07 / 2005

Web Interface Developer

Restyled a blogging platform. Created a colour picking widget.

XSLT, CSS, PHP, Javascript, HTML.

Hughesmedia

1999 - 2001

Web Developer

Built database-backed sites for clients. Built internal accounting system. Advocated and educated designers for the transition to CSS.

Acquired the hard way: the persistence and knowledge to work around Internet Explorer quirks.

Perl, PHP, MySQL, Linux, Apache, Sendmail, HTTP.

Education

Oxford Brookes University

2001 - 2005

BSc , Software Engineering

Languages

• English